Pradeep Kumar Bommak () Featured



Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Solution Architecture, HTML, Javascript, CSS, XML, Pega PRPC, Tomcat, Oracle



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 6 Month(s) Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services India Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Limited

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program

Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Solution

Architecture, HTML, Javascript, CSS, XML, Pega PRPC, Tomcat, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Overall around 4.2 years of IT experience in full Life Cycle Software Application Development, involved analysis, design, development, testing, documentation and maintenanceof PEGA PRPC application development.

Certified PRPC System Architect with strong Experience in development of Business Process Management (BPM) applications using PRPC.

Having of experience in the area of BPM - PEGA PRPC applications. As a core team member, I have worked in many areas of PRPC which includes Flows, Flow Actions, Section rules, data model, Harness rules, Activities, Data Transform, SLA, Declaratives, Connectors, user interface Design.

Designed PRPC Flows, Assignments, Utilities, Decisions, Declarative rules.

Worked on Different types of Flows (Starter flow, Screen flow, Sub flow).

Worked on Flow Actions (Connector and local).

Worked on Decision rules (Decision Table, Decision Tree, Map value and When).

Worked on Declarative rules like Declare on change, Declare Constraint, Declare Expression.

Work Experience

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited as Software Engineer

Oct 2018 to Till Date

Project#3: Arbella Mutual Insurance Client: Arbella insurance group Environment:PRPC7.x Duration: Oct 2018 to till date

Project Description:

Arbella Mutual Insurance Company is a Property and Casualty Insurance service provider. The project implementation automates the process of new business procurement across different lines of business. The project involves extensive integration with third party rules as per industry standards, and implementation of a rules based architecture that will facilitate modifications of business rules/processes in responseto changing market conditions. The next phase of the project aims at automating the entire suite of policy transactions including Policy Change, Cancellation, and Renewal as part of automating the entire Policy Administration System.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Understanding the client requirement and Functional Specification of the Application.

Preparing the Rules Log and Technical Design .

Preparing test cases and performing unit testing.

Preparation of final delivery note and communicate to onsite team

Taking active participation in the poker planning of each and every sprint.

Taking active participation during the sprint planning and design discussion during each and every sprint.

Reporting weekly status report.

Involved Client and Team meetings.

Configuration and support of enterprise software applications.

Knowledge of application servers such as Tomcat.

Knowledge of Windows operating systems.

Verizon India as Software Associate

Dec 2015 to Sep 2018

Project #2 :Claims Processing System Client :AIG Commercial Insurance

Environment : Pega RULES Process Commander (PRPC 7.x)

Duration: Apr 2017 to Sep 2018

Project Description:

AIG Commercial Insurance has embarked on a Claim Transformation initiative. This initiative intends to establish a Global Claims Platform which can be continuously enhanced to handle new Lines of Business and Geographies in turn resulting in consistent claim handling across all lines of businesses and geographies, improved customer experience and improved operational efficiency. One Claim offers a consolidated global approach to claims-entry, with an aim to improve performance around the speed and cost at which claims are processed to maximize the customer experience and improve overall service offered to our clients. One Claim positions AIG for efficient growth by providing a flexible end-to- end solution on a single global platform.

Roles& Responsibilities:

Creation of Activities and steps for business logic implementation and generate the Clipboard structure.

Supporting Team, Bug fixing. Working on developing Flows, Activities, Flow actions, Sections, Portals, and Decision rules in the PRPC.

Developing the application by performing the daily tasks as per the detailed design document

Implemented user interfaces using Sections, Harness and HTML stream rules.

Attending client meetings.

Worked on Assignments, Flow Actions.

Worked on user Interface rules, reports, decision and declarative rules, activities.

Developed search reports using List View and Summary View rules of PRPC.

Worked with Clipboard and Tracer for trouble shooting.

Involved in creating Class Structure and Access Group.

Project #1: Mortgage- Automobile from AIG

Client: AIG Commercial Insurance

Environment: Pega RULES Process Commander (PRPC 7.x)

Duration: Dec 2015 to Mar 2017

Project Description:

Vehicle Loan is a Web-Enabled Application that automates the Vehicle Loan Process. Application, sanction selecting eligible customer, preparing reports, preparing pre Sanction letter. Creation of loan account by authorized bank executive by providing loan amount, tenure, interest, feeding the details into the database. Instructing the clearing section to issue DD/Check to the customer

Roles& Responsibilities:

Implemented User Interfaces using Sections, Harness and Flow Actions.

Creating activities, when rules and decision rules.

Involved in ConfiguringPRPC smart shapes in business scenarios.

Unit testing and debugging using tracer, clipboard and rules inspector.

Worked on creating Reports.

Performed Unit Testing and sending the daily report.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Nalla Malla Reddy Engineering College, Hyderabad in 2014

IT Skills

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=8f6abf99fabd09a22d7c33435fc6c51a580e0b524c170e10001540510f5a...

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
PEGA PRPC 7.x, Oracle DB	
HTML, javascript, css, XML	
Tomcat 6.2, Microsoft Office	
windows 7,8,10	

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time